Clavin Fisher Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Clavin Fisher Papers.
undated, 1943-1998.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Fisher, Clavin C.
.25 linear feet.
Clavin C. Fisher was born on 12 July 1912, in Arlington, NJ, the son of Charles V. and Pearl (Burroughs) Fisher. He attended Bucknell University (BS, 1934) and New York University (MBA, 1937). Fisher began writing stories for children after retiring from a career with Aetna Life & Casualty (1937-1975) in Hartford, CT.
MSS19910045
Biography
Clavin C. Fisher was born on 12 July 1912, in Arlington, NJ, the son of Charles V. and Pearl (Burroughs) Fisher. He attended Bucknell University (BS, 1934) and New York University (MBA, 1937). Fisher began writing stories for children after retiring from a career with Aetna Life & Casualty (1937-1975) in Hartford, CT.
Scope and Content
The collection contains copies of publications in which the author published short stories and photocopies of correspondence, articles, reviews and related information.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of children's literature and associated artwork. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
A Spy at Ticonderoga Dodd Call No. CLC C1979
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Children's stories--Authorship.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Books.; Publications.
Occupations:
Author.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Donated by the author in 1991.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Papers, undated, 1943-1998
  - Articles, undated, 1975-1998 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, undated, 1974-1975 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Publications
    - “Blinker Blind”, 1946 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - “I Aim to Git Myself a Yankee!”, 1985 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - “The Magic Carpet Called Heli-Hiking” (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - A Spy at Ticonderga
      - Publicity and reviews, 1975 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - “Work Horse Legs”, 1943 (Box 1:, Folder 7)